<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="Rss.xsl"?>
<catalog>
  <article id="1">
    <title>Estonian city to be named 2024 European Capital of Culture</title>
    <description>For the first time since 2011, one of the 2024 European Capitals of Culture will once again be located in Estonia, and the Ministry of Culture and the Association of Estonian Cities on Wednesday announced a competition to determine which town or city will claim the title</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:26:45</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.err.ee/645659/estonian-city-to-be-named-2024-european-capital-of-culture</link>
    <id_category>1</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="2">
    <title>Health Insurance Fund to finance at least 102 ambulance squads next year</title>
    <description>The Estonian Health Insurance Fund (EUIF) will finance the operation of at least 102 ambulance squads, i.e. the de facto number of squads currently in operation, across Estonia in 2018.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:33:28</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.err.ee/650911/health-insurance-fund-to-finance-at-least-102-ambulance-squads-next-year</link>
    <id_category>2</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="3">
    <title>Tallinn announces procurement to renew Russian-language TV programs</title>
    <description>Tallinn City Office has announced procurements for the purchase of three Russian-language television shows currently being produced by the Russian-language TV channel Pervõi Baltiiski Kanal (PBK).&#13;
The procurements are for contracts concerning the production and airing of the programs "Dobroye Utro, Tallinn" (Good Morning, Tallinn), "Nasha Stolitsa" (Our Capital) and "Russki Vopros" (Russian Question), it appears from the register of public procurements.&#13;
All three programs are currently being produced and broadcast by PBK under an agreement valid through Dec. 31. Under this agreement, the three programs cost the city approximately €550,000 inclusive of VAT.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:35:00</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.err.ee/650966/tallinn-announces-procurement-to-renew-russian-language-tv-programs</link>
    <id_category>3</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="4">
    <title>Virtual snowman created by cyclist using app on London streets</title>
    <description>A cyclist has "drawn" an 88-mile (141km) virtual snowman across London.&#13;
Anthony Hoyte, from Cheltenham, spent 10 hours cycling the streets of the city, using the exercise and route sharing app Strava to "draw" the giant festive artwork.&#13;
The cyclist has created several virtual doodles including Fowl Play in Bristol, which took first prize in the city's Strava art competition in September.&#13;
He said: "I wanted to do something festive but it ended up so big."</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:36:40</pubDate>
    <link>http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-england-gloucestershire-42456773</link>
    <id_category>4</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="5">
    <title>Manchester United: Jose Mourinho says £300m spend not enough</title>
    <description>Manchester United boss Jose Mourinho said the £300m he has spent on his squad so far is "not enough", after their 2-2 draw with Burnley on Tuesday.&#13;
&#13;
Jesse Lingard scored a late equaliser but United are 12 points behind Premier League leaders Manchester City.&#13;
&#13;
"We are in the second year of trying to rebuild a football team that you know is not one of the best teams in the world," said Mourinho.&#13;
&#13;
He added: "Manchester City buy full-backs for the price of strikers."&#13;
&#13;
Mourinho was appointed United boss in May 2016 and broke the world record that summer to sign £89m midfielder Paul Pogba. He also recruited £30m defender Eric Bailly, and midfielder Henrikh Mkhitaryan for £26.3m.&#13;
&#13;
This year, United spent £75m on striker Romelu Lukaku, as well as £31m on defender Victor Lindelof and £40m for midfielder Nemanja Matic.&#13;
&#13;
Title rivals City, meanwhile, bought three defenders - Kyle Walker from Tottenham for an initial £45m, Benjamin Mendy from Monaco for £52m and Danilo from Real Madrid for £26.5m - as part of a summer outlay that topped £200m.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:38:44</pubDate>
    <link>http://www.bbc.com/sport/football/42488421</link>
    <id_category>4</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="6">
    <title>UK weather: Snow causes travel delays and power cuts</title>
    <description>Heavy snow and ice have disrupted road and air travel in parts of the UK and left thousands of homes without power.&#13;
&#13;
Drivers were at a standstill on the A14 in Northamptonshire for several hours, while a lorry crash on the M1 blocked the motorway.&#13;
&#13;
The Met Office has issued a yellow weather warning for ice overnight across most of the UK.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:40:36</pubDate>
    <link>http://www.bbc.com/news/uk-42490947</link>
    <id_category>5</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="7">
    <title>EU extends economic sanctions on Russia by six months</title>
    <description>The Council of the EU on Thursday decided to extend economic sanctions targeting specific sectors of the Russian economy through July 31, 2018.&#13;
This decision follows an update from French President Emmanuel Macron and German Chancellor Angela Merkel to the Dec. 14 European Council on the state of the implementation of the Minsk agreements, according to a Council press release.&#13;
The duration of the sanctions was linked on March 19, 2015 by the European Council to the complete implementation of the Minsk agreements, which was expected to take place by Dec. 31 of that year. As this did not happen, and due to the fact that the Minsk agreements still have yet to be fully implemented, the Council has decided to extend the sanctions by another six months.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:42:01</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.err.ee/650416/eu-extends-economic-sanctions-on-russia-by-six-months</link>
    <id_category>6</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="8">
    <title>Vulnerability discovered in spring kept quiet</title>
    <description>Estonian authorities were forced to close some ID-cards already in May and June after a University of Tartu research fellow came across a security vulnerability so severe that it allowed him to crack one of the cards and use it to fake a digital signature, a correspondence at Postimees’ disposal suggests.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:45:22</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.postimees.ee/4337279/vulnerability-discovered-in-spring-kept-quiet</link>
    <id_category>7</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="9">
    <title>Two more agreements on digital field concluded under Estonian EU presidency</title>
    <description>Two more agreements on the digital domain were concluded within the framework of the Estonian presidency of the Council of the EU last week.&#13;
During a meeting of envoys in Brussels, the Estonian EU presidency was unanimously authorized to continue developing the principles necessary for the free movement of non-personalized data, spokespeople for the Ministry of Economic Affairs and Communications said on Wednesday.&#13;
The second achievement was an agreement on the postal packages regulation, which will make package tariffs more transparent.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:47:24</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.err.ee/650912/two-more-agreements-on-digital-field-concluded-under-estonian-eu-presidency</link>
    <id_category>6</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="10">
    <title>Tallinn among most popular New Year's destinations for Russian tourists</title>
    <description>Tallinn, Riga and Helsinki are among most popular destinations for Russian residents spending New Year's Eve abroad, it can be seen from hotel statistics published by booking.com.&#13;
"For New Year's celebrations, from Jan. 1-8, the most popular destinations for Russians are Tallinn, Riga, Minsk, Prague and Helsinki," said booking.com.&#13;
The most popular Russian cities for domestic Russian and foreign tourists, meanwhile, include Moscow, St. Petersburg, Kazan, Nizhny Novgorod and Sochi.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:48:00</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.err.ee/650408/tallinn-among-most-popular-new-year-s-destinations-for-russian-tourists</link>
    <id_category>6</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="11">
    <title>Estonia's centennial begins with concerts, fireworks, president's speech</title>
    <description>With the arrival of 2018, Estonia's centennial begins. The jubilee year was inaugurated with a concert on Tallinn's Freedom Square, where President Kersti Kaljulaid also gave a speech.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:51:52</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.err.ee/651617/estonia-s-centennial-begins-with-concerts-fireworks-president-s-speech</link>
    <id_category>8</id_category>
  </article>
  <article id="12">
    <title>New funding application round aims to bring more culture, sports to Estonia</title>
    <description>A new application round with a total value of €2 million is to help bring large-scale international cultural and sporting events to Estonia which could not previously be realized due to funding constraints.&#13;
&#13;
The Ministry of Culture is to open a €2 million application round on Jan. 1 which aims to support large-scale international cultural and sporting events taking place in Estonia.&#13;
&#13;
According to Minister of Culture Indrek Saar (SDE), the new application round will provide an opportunity for organizers of cultural and sports events to bring large international events to Estonia. Applications can be submitted until the planned budget runs out.&#13;
&#13;
"These events will attract many foreign guests here, and the state will get additional tax receipts as a result," Saar was quoted by spokespeople as saying.&#13;
&#13;
Event budgets will fall into two categories this round — €65,000-€499,999.99 and €500,000+. Applications must be submitted to the ministry at least three months prior to the event taking place.</description>
    <pubDate>2018-01-01 20:56:03</pubDate>
    <link>https://news.err.ee/651505/new-funding-application-round-aims-to-bring-more-culture-sports-to-estonia</link>
    <id_category>4</id_category>
  </article>
</catalog>
